Aleksandr (Alex) Stepanov | Full Stack Software Developer

403-399-3035 | stepanov.hw@gmail.com | stepanovcodes.com in/aleksandr-stepanov | github.com/stepanovcodes

SUMMARY

I am a results-oriented, fast learner, and agile-driven full stack developer, focused on end-users' needs in a fast-paced and demanding environment. 5 years of Canadian and international software product management and technical sales experience informs everything that I do: from my ability to talk directly to the clients to finding concise solutions for challenging problems, ensuring optimal outcomes for both customers and business growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML | JavaScript | EJS | CSS | Python | SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: Node.js | Express | React | Next.js| TypeScript | TailwindCSS | Bootstrap | Sequelize | OAuth 2.0 | Django | Fluent 2 | Material UI

Utilities: CLI | Git | GitHub | VS Code | Mongoose | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Postman | openAl API | RESTful API | Jira | Figma | WITSML | WITS

Product Management: Agile Methodology | Software Development Lifecycle | Eliciting Requirements | Roadmaps | Agile Sprint Planning | Reviews & Metrics

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Child Hare | Solo Project | Next.js, Express, node.js, Sequelize.js, PostgreSQL, Mapbox GL JS

Full-Stack Developer | 2 weeks | Live | Github

• The app assists parents find child care options for their kids in Alberta, Canada

Theme Generator | Team Project | EJS, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, OpenAl

Backend Developer | 1 week | Live | Github

• Enhanced by AI, the app generates and previews styles exclusively based on theme names and descriptions

Solo Box & Solo WITSML Store | Rogii Canada Ltd. | React, C#, PostgreSQL, AWS

Product Owner | 2 years | Website

These two products aggregate and transmit well data from rig to office in real-time

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Product Owner

Calgary, AB

Roqii Canada Ltd. 2021 - 2023

- Launched and commercialized two software products in Canada, the USA, Australia, Latin America, and Kazakhstan
- Practiced the SCRUM Agile methodology through sprint planning, daily scrums, sprint reviews, sprint retrospectives
- Managed backlogs in Jira for three teams of ten developers, three QA specialists, designer, and business analyst
- Expressed requirements using user stories, story maps, and acceptance tests; visualized the requirements using wireframes and storyboards
- Ensured an accessible foundation by using Fluent design system, which meets or surpasses WCAG 2.1 AA standards
- Traveled to various locations, including rigs in the USA and Canada, to facilitate equipment installation

Technical Sales

Calgary, AB

Adaga Solutions, Ltd 2019 - 2021

- Promoted geosteering software, drilling analytics software, and WITSML server for Oil & Gas industry
- Performed troubleshooting, care about a customer (personal visits to customer sites, in-house training, online meetings, and telephone/email correspondence)

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

July 2023 - October 2023

 In this intensive 420-hour program at General Assembly's Bootcamp, I'm gaining hands-on experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB. I honed my skills in responsive design, API integration, secure authentication, and Agile methodologies. This comprehensive program is fostering my collaboration, problem-solving, and critical thinking abilities while enabling me to build a professional portfolio of full-stack web applications

University of Alberta Remote

Software Product Management Specialization

April 2023 - July 2023

Calgary, AB 2017-2019

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Applied Technology in Petroleum Engineering Honors / Entero Energy Software Award Winner

Heriot-Watt University

Master of Science in Petroleum Engineering

2011-2012

Master of Science in Petroleum Engineering Honors